<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>RimSynapse Core</name>
    <author>RimSynapse Team</author>
    <packageId>RimSynapse.Core</packageId>
    <url>https://github.com/RimSynapse/RimSynapse-Core</url>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <description>
[h1]RimSynapse Core[/h1]
[b]The foundational LM Studio and Ollama Connector for RimWorld.[/b]

RimSynapse Core is a powerful, asynchronous background engine that allows RimWorld mods to communicate with local Large Language Models (LLMs). On its own, this mod does not change gameplay, but it serves as the essential bridge required by all RimSynapse companion mods to bring true narrative intelligence to the Rim.

[h2]Features[/h2]
[list]
[*] [b]Universal Backend Support:[/b] Connects seamlessly to LM Studio, Ollama, or any OpenAI-compatible local API.
[*] [b]Background Threading:[/b] Never drops a frame. All LLM requests are queued, processed, and sanitized asynchronously on separate threads.
[*] [b]Dynamic Priority Queue:[/b] Intelligently manages hundreds of requests with an advanced Linux-style top-monitor queue system, prioritizing critical events and starving obsolete prompts.
[*] [b]Auto-Discovery:[/b] Automatically detects your active models and manages keep-alive pings to ensure your LLMs don't sleep when you need them.
[*] [b]GPU Monitoring:[/b] Built-in framework to keep track of local VRAM and processing overhead.
[/list]

[h2]Requirements[/h2]
[list]
[*] [b]Harmony[/b] is required.
[*] You must be running a local LLM server (like LM Studio or Ollama). We recommend 8B+ parameter models for optimal reasoning.
[/list]

[h2]Support the Project[/h2]
If you enjoy this framework and want to support the development of genuine AI-driven gameplay, consider buying me a coffee!
[url=https://buymeacoffee.com/archdukejim]☕ Buy me a coffee[/url]
    </description>
</ModMetaData>
