<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
    <name>RimSynapse - Core</name>
    <author>RimSynapse Team</author>
    <packageId>RimSynapse.Core</packageId>
    <url>https://github.com/RimSynapse/Core</url>
    <modVersion>0.5.0</modVersion>
    <supportedVersions>
        <li>1.5</li>
        <li>1.6</li>
    </supportedVersions>
    <modDependencies>
        <li>
            <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
            <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
            <steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
            <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
        </li>
    </modDependencies>
    <loadAfter>
        <li>brrainz.harmony</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
        <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Anomaly</li>
    </loadAfter>
    <incompatibleWith>
        <li>yancy.rimchat</li>
    </incompatibleWith>
    <description>
RimSynapse - Core
Official Wiki and Documentation: https://github.com/RimSynapse/Core/wiki

The foundational LLM Connector for RimWorld.

RimSynapse Core is a powerful, asynchronous background engine that natively brings narrative intelligence to RimWorld. It acts as the central brain of the RimSynapse ecosystem, intercepting vanilla events and directly altering the narrative tone of your game through its built-in storytelling mechanics, while also serving as the essential bridge required by all companion modules.

--- Features ---
- LLM Direct Action Console (Command in Plain English!): Control the game world using natural language! Open the Direct Action Console, type what you want in plain English (e.g. "Make Fred have 20 Shooting, remove the Bipolar trait from Sarah, and start a fire on the solar generator"), and watch the Storyteller LLM act as an active agent, translating your request into native in-game tool calls and executing them in real-time!
- Universal Backend Support: Connects seamlessly to LM Studio, Ollama, or any OpenAI-compatible local API. While RimSynapse's focus is on local models, with version 0.4.0, it is THE universal LLM connector!
- Background Threading: Never drops a frame. All LLM requests are queued, processed, and sanitized asynchronously on separate threads.
- Dynamic Priority Queue: Intelligently manages hundreds of requests with an advanced Linux-style top-monitor queue system, prioritizing critical events and starving obsolete prompts.
- Auto-Discovery: Automatically detects your active models and manages keep-alive pings to ensure your LLMs don't sleep when you need them.
- GPU Monitoring: Built-in framework to keep track of local VRAM and processing overhead.
- Event Tracking Ledger: Maintains a rolling, serializable backlog of major colony events. Core automatically snapshots the colony's wealth, nutrition, and every colonist's mood/health at the exact tick the event occurred, providing perfect chronological context to the LLM.
- Native Event Interception: Automatically captures major vanilla game events (marriages, legendary crafts, pawn deaths) via Harmony patches. It also natively intercepts standard storytelling events, raids, and quests to generate rich, contextual, multi-stage narratives via the LLM.
- Faction Perception Tracking: Each faction maintains subjective "Perceived Wealth" and "Perceived Strength" values for your colony, updated only through direct contact (visitors, traders, caravans).
- Memory Infrastructure: Provides the per-pawn memory bank, weighted tag system, and decay engine used by companion mods to give colonists persistent, evolving memories.
- Colony Snapshots: When events occur, the framework captures a snapshot of the colony's wealth, nutrition, and pawn status, providing rich context for AI-generated responses.
- Opportunistic Task Scheduling: A background task manager that feeds low-priority LLM requests (backstory generation, memory creation) into idle GPU cycles without impacting gameplay performance.

--- A Personal Note ---
AI is incredibly cool, and having a framework to utilize powerful, no-cost local models really appealed to me. RimWorld is relatively light on GPU overhead, making it the absolute perfect candidate to max out those graphics cards by running a local LLM in the background. My goal with RimSynapse is to push the boundaries of emergent storytelling using the hardware you already own.

--- Changelog ---
v0.4.0
- New Features! (Multi-provider LLM balancing, Image Generation Framework, and LLM Capabilities filtering)
v0.3.0
- Embedded Aura the storyteller into core
- Ecosystem Expansion (Introduced Chat, Factions, and WorldNews companion modules)
v0.2.1
- Bug fixes and stability improvements
v0.2.0
- Storyteller Update (Added the AI Storyteller module, now merged into Core)
v0.1.0
- Initial Release (Core framework, NVIDIA Tool, and Psychology module)

--- Roadmap and Future Goals ---
The initial roadmap for RimSynapse is now complete! Future updates will focus on maintaining the core framework and expanding functionality to allow other modders to build on top of it.

--- For Developers and Open Source ---
RimSynapse is an open-source framework designed to be easily hooked into by other modders. I highly encourage you to read the framework documentation and build your own LLM-driven mods!
- RimSynapse - Core Source and Docs: https://github.com/RimSynapse/Core
- RimSynapse - Psychology Source: https://github.com/RimSynapse/Psychology
- RimSynapse - Conversations Source: https://github.com/RimSynapse/Conversations
- RimSynapse - Factions Source: https://github.com/RimSynapse/Factions
- RimSynapse - WorldNews Source: https://github.com/RimSynapse/WorldNews
- RimSynapse - NVIDIA Tool Source: https://github.com/RimSynapse/NVIDIA-Tool

--- Compatibility Matrix ---
- Royalty DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates noble titles and psycast memories if active. Generates arrogant noble decrees and custom empire quests.
- Ideology DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates precepts, rituals, and conversions if active. Reframes quests as holy crusades and divine visions.
- Biotech DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates xenotypes, mechinators, and genetic history if active. Describes mechanitor threats as cold satellite broadcasts.
- Anomaly DLC: Compatible and Optional. Integrates entity encounters and void studies if active. Translates events into chilling whispers and void phenomena.

--- Requirements ---
- Harmony is required.
- You must be running a local LLM server (like LM Studio or Ollama). We recommend 8B+ parameter models for optimal reasoning.

--- Support the Project ---
If you enjoy this framework and want to support the development of genuine AI-driven gameplay, consider buying me a coffee!
Buy me a coffee: https://buymeacoffee.com/archdukejim
    </description>
</ModMetaData>